<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on WoOh&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/tags/mobile/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on WoOh&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.wooh.hu/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How I bought a Nexus 5X and a Leather Case</title>
      <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/how-i-bought-a-nexus5x-and-a-leather-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 21:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/how-i-bought-a-nexus5x-and-a-leather-cover/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;loosing-my-beloved-phone&#34;&gt;Loosing my beloved phone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accidentally crashed my beloved &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nexus_5&#34;&gt;Nexus 5&lt;/a&gt; three weeks ago. It fell off and I was very unlucky because it landed on it&amp;rsquo;s side, so it ripped apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I wanted to repair it, but if you look at the picture below, you&amp;rsquo;ll have no doubt that it&amp;rsquo;s not repairable. I&amp;rsquo;m using Google phones for a long time. My first google phone was a Nexus 4. I loved it so my wife had one too. That one was inherited by my mom. She&amp;rsquo;s still using it, so quality stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/crash.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Crashed Nexus 5&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last one was a Nexus 5. My wife also has one, because it is really good. It is fast, it does not cost a fortune and it&amp;rsquo;s reliable. My Nexus 5 was important for me, because I&amp;rsquo;m storing all my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_One-time_Password_Algorithm&#34;&gt;TOTP&lt;/a&gt; codes on my phone. Or at least I stored&amp;hellip; so every time when my phone breaks down I&amp;rsquo;m in a big trouble. I need to disable the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two-factor_authentication&#34;&gt;2FA&lt;/a&gt; everywhere using the backup codes or SMS and re-add them one-by-one. This is a pain in the ass actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; also has a TOTP field type, so I was smarter this time and migrated all 2FA TOTP codes temporary to my 1Password. The biggest problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I ordered something cool to replace the 1Password/Google Authenticator. More to come soon in a next blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nexus-5x&#34;&gt;Nexus 5X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I had to decide which phone to buy, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/nexus/5x/&#34;&gt;LG Nexus 5X&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/nexus/6p/&#34;&gt;Huawei Nexus 6P&lt;/a&gt;. The decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that hard. I hate huge phones and unfortunately all vendors are creating larger and larger screens&amp;hellip; luckily the Nexus 5X isn&amp;rsquo;t that much larger than the Nexus 5 and it&amp;rsquo;s price is pretty friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a strange rule: I don&amp;rsquo;t buy phones more than 100,000 HUF ($363). The Nexus 5X costs $334 + VAT. Pretty good price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/google_nexus_5x.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nexus vs. Nexus 5x&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Nexus 5X is in your hands, the look and feel is almost the same like a Nexus 5. Except the fingerprint scanner at the back. That is pretty handy and useful. Makes it very convenient to unlock my phone. The screen is wider, the system is a bit faster, better button positioning, but in general it feels like Nexus 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nillkin-qin-leather-flip-case&#34;&gt;Nillkin qin leather flip case&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be quite honest I had a cover for my Nexus 5 but it was pretty poky, and I removed it a few month ago. But I wanted to have something elegant for my 5X. Many many years ago, I had my fist Nexus 4 case from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mytrendyphone.co.uk&#34;&gt;MyTrendyPhone&lt;/a&gt;, and I ordered a lot from there. Unfortunately the Nexus 5X is not available in Hungary (so actually I had to order it from abroad), so due to this there are no covers available in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/oldalt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Side&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On MyTrendyPhone I found a pretty elegant, stylish cover for my 5X. It&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mytrendyphone.co.uk/shop/lg-nexus-5x-182689p.html&#34;&gt;Nillkin Qin Leather Flip Case&lt;/a&gt;. It was love for the first sight. I knew I wanted it. The bad thing is that the shipment costs alost the same as the cover itself, but well I had no option. I had to buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/belulrol.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inside&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It arrived in about 2 days, they shipped it via UPS. I was suprised that the packaging itself was elegant too. I love to buy things from MyTrendyPhone, because they sell quality stuff. I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty satisfied with this company. I&amp;rsquo;m also satisfied with Google and LG, they manufactured another awesome mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/csukva.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Closed&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>