<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WoOh&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/tags/toshiba/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Adam Papai</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-06-22 15:55:56 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Switching to Chromebook - Part III.</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-3/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 15:55:56 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-3/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier I mentioned that I bought an Acer C720P Chromebook. A few weeks ago my new Chromebook arrived: Toshiba Chromebook 2 (2015). The Acer is really great to carry around, the touchscreen is pretty cool too, but the 11.6&amp;rdquo; is way too small for real development. If you use it for development, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to overview your code, you need to scroll up and down a lot of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recap:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case if you missed the previous posts. You can read them below. Note that this post is rather a review than a &lt;strong&gt;how to switch&lt;/strong&gt;, so stay tuned and wait for part IV. where I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about OpenVPN, L2TP/IPsec, Printing, and things that aren&amp;rsquo;t working properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-1/&#34;&gt;Switching to Chromebook - Part I.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-2/&#34;&gt;Switching to Chromebook - Part II.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variety:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Variety&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of posts about what&amp;rsquo;s the best Chromebook. Just to mention a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techradar.com/news/mobile-computing/laptops/best-chromebooks-top-5-chromebooks-in-the-us-1233696&#34;&gt;10 best Chromebooks 2016: top Chromebooks reviewed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.laptopmag.com/best-chromebooks&#34;&gt;Best Chromebooks 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2413071,00.asp&#34;&gt;The 10 Best Chromebooks of 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebooks&#34;&gt;The best Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of reviews about the older models and the brand new ones too. I wish I could buy all of them. But I can&amp;rsquo;t just spend a lot of money. And their biggest pro is that they&amp;rsquo;re inexpensive - compared to other notebooks of course. So you only need one. But which one you should buy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly all posts agreed that the Toshiba Chromebook 2 is the best after the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.google.com/chromebook-pixel/&#34;&gt;Google Pixel 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toshiba-chromebook-2:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Toshiba Chromebook 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re talking about the Toshiba Chromebook 2 note that there are 3 (actually 4) Toshiba Chromebooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toshiba | CB35-A3120    | 2955U  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; | 2GB    |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toshiba | CB35-B3340    | N2840  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; | 4GB    |&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toshiba | CB35-C3300    | 3215U  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; | 4GB    | Full HD, Backlit Keyboard&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toshiba | CB35-C3350    | i3-5015U &amp;nbsp;| 4GB | Full HD, Backlit Keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know what is the best. Toshiba released 4 Chromebooks in 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toshiba-cb35-a3120-chromebook:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Toshiba CB35-A3120 Chromebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is known as &lt;strong&gt;Toshiba Chromebook&lt;/strong&gt;. It was the first Toshiba Chromebook. It is just an average Chromebook, you definitely don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy this. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2453427,00.asp&#34;&gt;Read the PCMag review here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toshiba-cb35-b3340-chromebook-2:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Toshiba CB35-B3340 Chromebook 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first &lt;strong&gt;Toshiba Chromebook 2&lt;/strong&gt;. Customers bought it were pretty satisfied. It does not have a fan! So it&amp;rsquo;s pretty quiet, but the CPU speed is limited. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2470486,00.asp&#34;&gt;Read the PCMag review here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toshiba-cb35-c3300-cb35-c3350-chromebook-2:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Toshiba CB35-C3300 / CB35-C3350 Chromebook 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last 2 model is almost the same. The only difference is the CPU. The CB35-C3300 has &lt;strong&gt;Intel Celeron 3215U&lt;/strong&gt;. You can buy with a faster &lt;strong&gt;Intel Celeron i3-5015U8&lt;/strong&gt; CPU, but reviews say: It does not really worth it, it only reduces the battery life and you won&amp;rsquo;t really feel the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Chromebook you definitely want to buy is the Toshiba CB35-C3300 Chromebook 2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PCMag has review about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2498023,00.asp&#34;&gt;CB35-C3350&lt;/a&gt; too, but they did not like the battery life. As I said before: if you buy it with an i3 CPU, the battery life won&amp;rsquo;t be tha same. Both C3300 and C3350 has a fan, so it won&amp;rsquo;t be that silent than the previous two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you live in US, you can buy the C3300 for about $300 USD. If you live in Hungary just like me, it will cost $299.99 + $123.69 Shipping &amp;amp; Import Fees Deposit. Amazon handles everything for you. You&amp;rsquo;ll get it in no time, which means about a week. Since there are absolutely no Chromebooks in Hungary you can&amp;rsquo;t even try it out first, so it was a pig in a poke. How excited I was when it arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-own-review:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;My own review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only compare the &lt;strong&gt;Toshiba CB35-C3300 Chromebook 2&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Acer C720P&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-1/&#34;&gt;part I.&lt;/a&gt; I already covered the Acer specs and the first user experience, so if you&amp;rsquo;re interested, read it now. But just for sure I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you a few sexy photos about the Acer C720P to catch your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/acer/acer_box_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/acer/acer_box_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/acer/acer_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in it&amp;hellip; well I&amp;rsquo;m not using it anymore so you can buy it. I only used it for about a week and Powerwashed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;boxing:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Boxing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to Toshiba. I was pretty excited when it arrived. I quickly removed the wrapping and saw &amp;ldquo;the box&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The box foreshadows that it is much bigger than the Acer, meanwhile even the box is so thin. The Acer&amp;rsquo;s box is less thinner. Strange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the box you&amp;rsquo;ll find the power cable (US type), documents, and the chromebook itself. Everything is properly covered and packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The material is plastic. The previous ones were less plastic-feel, but it won&amp;rsquo;t annoy you. What is a bit annoying is that the edges are a bit sharp. The top material is bumpy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;backlit-keyboard:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Backlit keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 5&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backlit keyboard feels like your MacBook Pro. I&amp;rsquo;m not joking. I immediately switched off the lights and increased the backlit. It&amp;rsquo;s so smooth when you type. As I mentioned before I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Simplified_Keyboard&#34;&gt;dvorak typist&lt;/a&gt; so the keyboard has a very high priority in my life. If the keyboard is not comfortable I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to type hours on it. Of course I could still attach my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLA22LL/A/magic-keyboard-us-english&#34;&gt;Apple Wireless Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; to it via bluetooth, but I&amp;rsquo;d rather not do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You only need to get used to the shape and location of the &lt;strong&gt;enter&lt;/strong&gt;. Also the backslash is a bit too right, but still can easily reach it with my fourth finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Screen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screen in gorgeous and beautiful! I has a full-HD resolution of 1920 x 1080, but it can do 2400 x 1350 too. This won’t be to everyone’s tastes. Text, buttons and other items on screen do look a fair bit smaller. If your eyesight isn’t the best you may find yourself zooming in or manually switching to a lower resolution so you’re not constantly squinting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t using an external screen, you would need to use 125% zoom on all sites to be able to read the text. But I can live with this, it&amp;rsquo;s not that annoying. Customers are complaining about the small text, so probably in a few months there will be some fix. The icons can&amp;rsquo;t be enlarged, so sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find the app you want to launch, because they&amp;rsquo;re so small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dimensions:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Dimensions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of dimensions it has the same dimensions as a MacBook Pro 13&amp;rdquo; but it weights less. See the photos below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 7&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 8&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 9&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 11&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sound:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Sound&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big kudos to the Toshiba team for building such a great machine. The sound is perfect! Toshiba teamed up with Skullcandy and built the speakers behind the keyboard. But somehow it sounds like a hifi system. Just look at the Skullcandy logo, it tells everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/toshiba/toshiba_12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Toshiba 12&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ports:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Ports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it has USB 3.0 and 2.0, a SD Card reader and a HDMI. Almost enough. I hope they&amp;rsquo;ll include USB-C in the next model, and I would like to charge it via an USB-C port just like the Google Pixel 2. I have a Nexus 5X and I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to charge my phone using my Chromebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that it comes with the US power cord, so in case if you want to use it in Hungary, you need converter slots. Luckily I have a lot since we travel a lot to US and Japan, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a big issue. What&amp;rsquo;s more I use more US cords than EU cords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;battery:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Battery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery life seems to be somewhere between 5-7hrs depending on the brightness level. During evening hours the lowest brightness level works too, so you gain a lot of battery life, but you can work in sunshine too, the screen is pretty bright if you set the brightness to the higher level. So your Mac&amp;rsquo;s battery won&amp;rsquo;t last longer, maybe a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ask how I can live with 4G memory only? Well to be quite honest I have around 23-40 tabs open all the time, listening to youtube without any problem at all. I feel it fast, no slowdown. On the Acer C720P I felt the slowdown after ~10 tabs, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt it on the Toshiba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing you&amp;rsquo;ll notice is that after a few tabs, the fan will start to spin. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty quiet, but can be annoying in a very quiet room. I haven&amp;rsquo;t got used to it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary:42397d88ec47ccd52580c3dda0ba32e8&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very satisfied with this Chromebook. I just feels like a Mac, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s way less expensive and the IPS Full HD screen amazes me every time when I switch it on. If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about buying a Chromebook you should buy only this and not anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;em&gt;If you live in Hungary and want to see a Chromebook with your own eyes and try it out, you can ping me and I can show you somewhere in Budapest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
