<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WoOh&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Adam Papai</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-06-15 18:56:42 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Switching to Chromebook - Part II.</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-2/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 18:56:42 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-2/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this part I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you a few applications I was using on a Mac and tell you how to migrate them to a Chromebook or what alternatives you can use if the application is not available at all for a Chromebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I could compress everything in three small chunk post but it seems that&amp;rsquo;s impossible. So expect a lot more blog posts from me on this specific topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hipchat:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;HipChat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/hipchat.png&#34; alt=&#34;HipChat&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably using the native HipChat app on your Mac. There is no native HipChat app for ChromeOS, but you can use the web version. You just need to login to &lt;strong&gt;yourdomain.hipchat.com&lt;/strong&gt;, log-in and click on the &lt;em&gt;Launch the web app&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/hipchat_web.png&#34; alt=&#34;HipChat web app&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it looks exactly the same as the native MacOS app. It&amp;rsquo;s convenient. It will ask you to enable the Chrome desktop notifications which is useful. You can also configure not to notify you, or notify only if you&amp;rsquo;re mentioned or only receive notifications from specific channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web app has the same feeling as the native app. Same shortcuts, same UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;slack:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/slack_rgb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Slack&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most powerful group chat client with awesome 3rd party integrations. There isn&amp;rsquo;t any mentionable difference between the native app and the web app. You also need to enable the desktop notifications in Chrome to receive notifications. You can also switch between different slack accounts like in the native app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com&#34;&gt;https://slack.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;twitter:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a hardcore twitter user, so twitter is manadatory for me. I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetdeck-by-twitter/id485812721?mt=12&#34;&gt;TweetDeck by Twitter&lt;/a&gt; on my Mac and I was a bit afraid what I can use after switching to Chromebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/twitter.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have pretty good news! Tweetdeck has a web app too, which looks exactly the same as the TweedDeck by Twitter app for mac. Except it does not eat up a lot of memory. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t even recognize that this is not the Mac app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tweetdeck.twitter.com&#34;&gt;https://tweetdeck.twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;evernote:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; addict. My wife grew up in Japan, so she loves to plan every second of our life. In 10 years I had to learn how to plan and how to be more productive. I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; as my GTD tool of choice. Before Evernote I tried several things before. First I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://culturedcode.com/things/&#34;&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt; which only supported OS X and iOS. I need a tool for my phone too, so I migrated all my lists to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wunderlist.com/&#34;&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/a&gt; which was pretty awesome, but my wife was using Evernote so finally she convinced me to switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/evernote-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Evernote&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.evernote&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/evernote-capture-notes-sync/id281796108?mt=8&#34;&gt;OS X&lt;/a&gt; Evernote app is really good. It has a really good UI with all features you need for GTD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.evernote.com/blog/2015/08/13/introducing-the-new-evernote-web-client/&#34;&gt;Evernote Web Client&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t that good, but luckily there is a &lt;em&gt;beta&lt;/em&gt; version available. You can opt-in. Additionally Evernote has just introduced it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/google-drive/&#34;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; support which is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all my documents are google documents on a Chromebook it&amp;rsquo;s very convenient to use Evernote Beta Web Client and simply mix my notes in evernote with the google documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;skype:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skype is a very popular IM and Video application. Skype keeps the world talking, for free. Share, message and call - now with group video on mobile and tablet too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/skype.png&#34; alt=&#34;Skype&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no ChromeOS native app, but there is an alternative solution: Skype has an alternative &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.skype.com&#34;&gt;Skype for Web (Beta)&lt;/a&gt; application. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to make voice calls or video calls, but you can use Skype as an IM. I rarely used Skype for video/voice calls so I&amp;rsquo;m ok with this workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you used Skype for voice and video calls, you need something else. The obvious choice is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hangouts.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/a&gt;. Nowadays almost everybody has a google account, but even without a google account, you can join a hangout meeting without the requirement of a Google account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/hangouts.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hangouts&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a native ChromeOS app available: &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-hangouts/knipolnnllmklapflnccelgolnpehhpl?hl=en&#34;&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/a&gt;. Get it and try it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sublime-2-pycharm-and-vim:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Sublime 2, PyCharm and Vim&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to know, that there is no native ChromeOS IDE available at the moment. So no way to use Sublime or PyCharm or any well known editor. Sublime Text and PyCharm are available for OS X, Windows and Linux only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to use a cloud IDE. At the first glance it sounds weird. Using a cloud editor? How? How can I manage/upload files there? Ohh boy, there are plenty of services out there. They are pretty good replacement for Sublime 2 and PyCharm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-ide:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Cloud IDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I read o lot of articles about the best cloud IDEs. There are around 10 in the market at the moment, but not all are suitable for me. I have expectations of a Cloud IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;trial-free-tier-good-pricing-plan:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Trial / Free tier /  Good pricing plan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can spend my money on other things, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend all my spare money on a Cloud IDE. It should have a &lt;em&gt;trial&lt;/em&gt; - full version - to try it out. I don&amp;rsquo;t like when the trial does not provide all features, because I can&amp;rsquo;t really decide whether sign-up for a paid plan or evaluate another service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should have a &lt;em&gt;free tier plan&lt;/em&gt; , so I could get a very minimal but 100% usable environment. I can live with 512MB memory and a very little disk space too. CPU is not important for me, I won&amp;rsquo;t compile or mine bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;encapsulated-private-workspaces:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Encapsulated / Private Workspaces&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually the free tier plans are available but don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to protect your sensitive data. They&amp;rsquo;re open to everyone. So a free tier should at least provide 1 private / encapsulated environment, so I can work on &lt;em&gt;non open-source projects&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;terminal-emulator:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Terminal Emulator&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also expect a Linux environment with root access, so I can install a lot of things. It can be a Docker on anything else I don&amp;rsquo;t really mind. It does not have to run 0-24. Enough if it&amp;rsquo;s running when I&amp;rsquo;m working with it. If I can open a few ports and test my work that&amp;rsquo;s also a good pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-ide-should-be-cool:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;The IDE should be cool&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I expect a cool, customisable editor with awesome color schemes and themes. I don&amp;rsquo;t like cloud editors with the look of the 90&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud9-ide:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Cloud9 IDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first choice of Cloud IDE was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://c9.io&#34;&gt;Cloud9 IDE&lt;/a&gt;. It has all the features I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give them &lt;strong&gt;9 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why not &lt;strong&gt;10 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IDE looks pretty awesome. Behind the scenes it&amp;rsquo;s running &lt;a href=&#34;http://nwjs.io/&#34;&gt;NW.js&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re not using a Chromebook you could even download it and use it as your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/cloud9_pricing.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud9IDE pricing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with their pricing is that the next step after the free is &lt;strong&gt;$19&lt;/strong&gt; / mo. That is too much for such a service. I don&amp;rsquo;t need unlimited private and public workspaces. I might only need a bit more disk or memory on my 1 private workspace, but I will never need more than let&amp;rsquo;s say 2-3 workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d rather pay &lt;strong&gt;$4 - $5&lt;/strong&gt; for 2-3 optional public/private workspaces instead. For now, the free tier plan is definitely enough for me. It works like charm. The free tier gives you &lt;strong&gt;512MB&lt;/strong&gt; memory and &lt;strong&gt;2GB&lt;/strong&gt; disk space. More than what you&amp;rsquo;ll ever need in case if you&amp;rsquo;re not using maven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default you can use it as one git repo per workspace, but I&amp;rsquo;d recommend not using that approach. I have around 30 repos checked out in one workspace and still have a lot of disk space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/cloud9_template.png&#34; alt=&#34;c9.io template&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re creating a new workspace, you can choose a default template. It means your linux box will have a lot of specific things pre-installed and will spare you space, becaues you won&amp;rsquo;t need to install them. Everything you install on your linux box will be counted too in your disk usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/cloud91.png&#34; alt=&#34;cloud9ide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating the workspace it will boot up your linux box called container (docker) and put some default files on it&amp;rsquo;s disks and pop up the UI. I found it very convenient. You can highly customize the UI. Change the layout, but I think the default works the best. You have your file lest on the left, edited files on the top/right and your terminal on bottom/right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a paid customer, you can even use SSH workspaces so you can use your own box as a workspace. Sometimes that would be useful, but since I&amp;rsquo;m on a free plan, I can SSH in, sync my files and do what I need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/cloud9ide.png&#34; alt=&#34;c9.io&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to mention a few Cloud9 IDE features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Autocompletion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and Upload Files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File Revision History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP Mounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keybindings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Cursors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search and Replace in Files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supported Languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax Highlighting and Themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental Features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.c9.io/docs/&#34;&gt;Cloud9 Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the basic applications have web version which is pretty convenient and makes the switch easier. However if you&amp;rsquo;re a hardcore Skype user, you&amp;rsquo;ll experience degraded service compared to the Windows/Mac application. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to make voice/video calls, but you can write to your contacts and tell them that they can reach you via Google Hangouts. At least this is a good point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HipChat&lt;/strong&gt;:  &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slack&lt;/strong&gt;:   &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;:   &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evernote&lt;/strong&gt;:   &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IDE/Vim&lt;/strong&gt;:   &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skype&lt;/strong&gt;:   &amp;#10007;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-comes-next:b63520bef825180c2999b1f9d2c55e30&#34;&gt;What comes next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating 3 different Cloud IDE service at the moment and it worth to mention them. In the next blog post I&amp;rsquo;d love to cover those too. They seem to be competitive to Cloud9 IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I bought another Chromebook because the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acer.com/ac/en/US/content/series/c720&#34;&gt;Acer C720P&lt;/a&gt; was too small. My current Chromebook is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B015806LMM/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;Toshiba Chromebook 2 - 2015 Edition (CB35-C3300) Full HD, Backlit Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and I plan to write a review blog post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more I&amp;rsquo;d love to compare the Acer to Toshiba to help you decide what to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a list of &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s not working on a Chromebook&amp;rdquo;, and I&amp;rsquo;d love to share those with you. If you&amp;rsquo;re not a DevOps, you might not need those applications or tools, but if you&amp;rsquo;re a tech junkie, you probably need those and luckily I have workarounds too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Switching to Chromebook - Part I.</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-1/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 16:23:11 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-1/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Let me share my story with you. This is a long one so I&amp;rsquo;ll split it into a few small chunks so you won&amp;rsquo;t get bored (hopefully). This is a story about how I changed my MacBook Pro to a Chromebook.  I never thought it would be ever possible, but it was. And it&amp;rsquo;s relatively easy and convenient.  You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to use all your current applications on a Chromebook but there are pretty good alternatives and I&amp;rsquo;m 100% sure you&amp;rsquo;ll like them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part covers information about me and about my work, what kind of apps I use, how I use them and what kind of notebooks I was using before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;emotionally-attached-to-apple:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;Emotionally attached to Apple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a very long time Apple fan. I bought almost every gadget they made, except the iPhone. iPhone is an exception, because it&amp;rsquo;s so much overpriced and the Google reference phones are way better and cheaper than the iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought my first iPod (Dock Connector) 20G around 2004, earphones, in-ear earphones, iBook G3, iBook G4 iMac G3, iMac G4, iMac intel, PowerBook G4, MacBook Pro, MacBook Air, iPod Shuffle&amp;hellip; so I spent a lot of money buying these awesome gadgets. Luckily most of the MacBooks were paid by my actual employer. I loved them and still love them. All of my MacBook Pros are CTO setup, so all of them had extra memory + extra CPU + extra disk, because I thought I need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple gadgets are really cool. From UX perspective: they&amp;rsquo;re all perfect. Well, almost perfect, but usually better than other things. The big con is usually their price. All of&amp;rsquo;em are overpriced. Yeah. Let&amp;rsquo;s face the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-m-a-devops-engineer:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a DevOps Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time (50%) using a terminal and 50% in a web browser. I was tracking this with RescueTime. For more than 2 years I&amp;rsquo;m not using any e-mail clients like &amp;ldquo;Mail&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;PostBox&amp;rdquo;. I was a pretty huge PostBox fan too, but it used up 2-3G memory so I finally deleted it from my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I mostly need is a terminal and internet connection, sometimes with a VPN, and a browser. It&amp;rsquo;s just a convenient fact, that I install a lot of console applications on my mac using brew or macports. So I can run a few things locally, but in the end everything will be executed on a server or on a JenkinsCI server. No real reason to run things locally. Git branching is pretty cheap and a jenkins job can be configured to run only my testing branch, so I can commit a lot of trash and wait jenkins for doing it&amp;rsquo;s job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other applications I was running are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HipChat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TweetDeck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sublime 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCharm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1Password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yubico Authenticator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Part II. I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how can you use these applications or how can you switch to other similar applications so you won&amp;rsquo;t feel youself blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another cool MacBook feature is that if I close it, it goes to sleep. If I open it, it wakes up and I can continue my work where I left it off. This is the main reason why I love the Mac. Linux and *BSD were pretty bad at it and I gave it up after a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s be honest: using a Mac for a terminal and a web browser is a bit luxury. A MacBook Pro costs around $1,500 - $2,000 USD. You can get them a bit cheaper of course, but those aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;powerful&amp;rdquo; enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/macbookpro.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MacBook Pro/Air Bulldog Decal&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yeah, a MacBook Pro/Air is pretty trendy and can stick cool decals on the back, looks great, made from awesome material and has a great smell for 1-2 month. But I think that&amp;rsquo;s all. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that the fact it&amp;rsquo;s running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/osx/&#34;&gt;OS X&lt;/a&gt; would be listed in the pros column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;previous-attempts:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;Previous attempts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I was using Macs, I used custom built notebooks with NetBSD/OpenBSD as my operating system of choice. Those were pretty powerful machines at that time. 2x2.8Ghz CPU with HyperThreading technology. I loved it. After using iBooks for a few years I though what if I can switch back and use *BSD or Linux on a notebook, so I bought a Toshiba. I tried everything but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to &amp;ldquo;like&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;love&amp;rdquo; it, so finally I gave it to a friend. I bougth another MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow even a Toshiba notebook with a Linux/BSD wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to impress me. I was disappoitned but happy with my new MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-i-decided-to-switch:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;Why I decided to switch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month ago I read some news on &lt;a href=&#34;http://hup.hu&#34;&gt;Hungarian Unix Portal&lt;/a&gt; about Chromebooks. The news said that more chromebooks were sold in 2016 Q1-Q2 than MacBooks. This time I couldn&amp;rsquo;t ignore this information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 years ago when I was in San Francisco, the Google Pixel had been just introduced. It was really horrible, everybody said that it&amp;rsquo;s a completely useless laptop. So I started to ignore all news related to Chromebooks, until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiment-on-a-macbook-pro:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;Experiment on a MacBook Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before buying anything, I wanted to make sure that I can survive with only a Chrome browser on my Mac for more than a day. So I suddenly closed all my running apps on my Mac except a Google Chrome. I read a lot of articles about cloud editors and alternatives to local editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to know how to use SSH from a browser. Another big question was the my password manager. The chrome extension for &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is only a wrapper around the local application, so I finally ended up using LastPass which has a web version. 1Password also has a web version, but that costs way more than LastPass. So actually I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a few promising cloud IDEs. They mostly provide an ubuntu box too as a terminal. They&amp;rsquo;re docker containers, I can install anything I need on them. They have free subscriptions but they&amp;rsquo;re mostly enough for me. I only need 1 private workspace with a 2G disk and 512M memory. More than what I really need. I also have a personal server at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com&#34;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; so if I need more disk space or capacity, I just used that server too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiment-on-a-chromebook:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;Experiment on a Chromebook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 7 days I was still using only a browser on my Mac so I tought it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to move ahead and find a cheap used Chromebook for a real ChomeOS experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately in Hungary there are no Chromebooks at all, but luckily we have a local ebay like site which has a few used chromebooks listed. I was looking for a Chromebook with 4G memory. The 2G ones are a joke I guess. Finally I found one for &lt;strong&gt;$198 USD&lt;/strong&gt;. It was the &lt;strong&gt;Acer C720P Touch&lt;/strong&gt; Chromebook. It has a small screen but has HDMI to extend the screen to my monitor which could be definitely enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/acer/acer_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer C720P&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.6&amp;rdquo; HD Multi-Touch LCD&lt;br /&gt;
Intel Celeron CPU 2955U&lt;br /&gt;
4GB DDR3 Low Voltage Memory&lt;br /&gt;
16G SSD&lt;br /&gt;
HDMI&lt;br /&gt;
USB&lt;br /&gt;
SD CARD reader&lt;br /&gt;
Acer Nplify 802.11a/b/g/n - BT 4.0&lt;br /&gt;
Acer Crystal Eye HD Webcam&lt;br /&gt;
3-cell Li-Polymer battery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a good little laptop. The keyboard is a bit small, but I can still type on it. I&amp;rsquo;m a dvorak typists so the keyboard is important. If it&amp;rsquo;s too small (like the EeePCs way back) I can&amp;rsquo;t type on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-time-user-experience-ftue:d2cb8c1412cb17e378636742e952556d&#34;&gt;First-time User Experience (FTUE)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I bought it as a used laptop it wasn&amp;rsquo;t used at all. It was brand new, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even unboxed, so I felt the excitement when I started to unbox it. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen a non-apple laptop for a good amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I unpacked it, I pressed the power button and wow! After about 4 seconds the login screen welcomed me. Holy cow! It&amp;rsquo;s fast. Let&amp;rsquo;s login. I had to select my country, select my keyboard layout (dvorak is supported by default) and select a wifi network. Without a wifi network you can&amp;rsquo;t login for the very first time. Later you can, but for the very first time you need to be connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to enter your google username and password. My Google account is protected by a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yubico.com/products/yubikey-hardware/yubikey4/&#34;&gt;Yubikey 4&lt;/a&gt; which is a USB security key used as my 2FA of choice. On my Mac I even used it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Yubico_YubiKeyMacOSXLogin_en.pdf&#34;&gt;challenge response&lt;/a&gt;. After I entered my username and password it asked me to use my security key aka my yubikey. I just pressed it and voilla! I was logged in. So note that your USB security key will work like charm on a Chromebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few seconds it synced down all my Chrome data from the cloud including my browsing history, bookmarks, chrome extensions and chrome applications like &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.naver.line.android&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Line Messenger&lt;/a&gt;. Pretty convenient!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default ChromeOS won&amp;rsquo;t ask a password when waking up from a sleep, so before starting any work on this machine I set this up. Unfortunately here isn&amp;rsquo;t an option to enforce the presence of a security key (like yubikey), but I can live without it. The login is a pretty cheap operation so you can just logout instead of just lock your machine. All browser tabs will be reloaded after logging back and you can continue your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened up a Chrome and stared to browse. Everything seemed smooth, fast response from the browser. So far so good! Attached my external monitor to the Chromebook without any issue. I attached my Logitech HD Webcam to it and it was able to use it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/chromeos/acer/acer_external.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acer + External&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we only covered a few things, 3 out of 4 are working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;#10003;] Yubico 4 (Authentication)&lt;br /&gt;
[&amp;#10003;] Webcam&lt;br /&gt;
[&amp;#10003;] External monitor&lt;br /&gt;
[&amp;#10007;] 1Password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/post/switching-to-chromebook-part-2&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to migrate your digital life to a Chromebook from your Mac and what problems you will encounter. I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you what kind of cloud editors I stated to use and what will work on your Chromebook and what won&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>How I bought a Nexus 5X and a Leather Case</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/how-i-bought-a-nexus5x-and-a-leather-cover/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 21:04:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/how-i-bought-a-nexus5x-and-a-leather-cover/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;loosing-my-beloved-phone:96b1c56c0446a93b7db9992f2b490a22&#34;&gt;Loosing my beloved phone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accidentally crashed my beloved &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nexus_5&#34;&gt;Nexus 5&lt;/a&gt; three weeks ago. It fell off and I was very unlucky because it landed on it&amp;rsquo;s side, so it ripped apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I wanted to repair it, but if you look at the picture below, you&amp;rsquo;ll have no doubt that it&amp;rsquo;s not repairable. I&amp;rsquo;m using Google phones for a long time. My first google phone was a Nexus 4. I loved it so my wife had one too. That one was inherited by my mom. She&amp;rsquo;s still using it, so quality stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/crash.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Crashed Nexus 5&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last one was a Nexus 5. My wife also has one, because it is really good. It is fast, it does not cost a fortune and it&amp;rsquo;s reliable. My Nexus 5 was important for me, because I&amp;rsquo;m storing all my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_One-time_Password_Algorithm&#34;&gt;TOTP&lt;/a&gt; codes on my phone. Or at least I stored&amp;hellip; so every time when my phone breaks down I&amp;rsquo;m in a big trouble. I need to disable the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two-factor_authentication&#34;&gt;2FA&lt;/a&gt; everywhere using the backup codes or SMS and re-add them one-by-one. This is a pain in the ass actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; also has a TOTP field type, so I was smarter this time and migrated all 2FA TOTP codes temporary to my 1Password. The biggest problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I ordered something cool to replace the 1Password/Google Authenticator. More to come soon in a next blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nexus-5x:96b1c56c0446a93b7db9992f2b490a22&#34;&gt;Nexus 5X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I had to decide which phone to buy, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/nexus/5x/&#34;&gt;LG Nexus 5X&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/nexus/6p/&#34;&gt;Huawei Nexus 6P&lt;/a&gt;. The decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that hard. I hate huge phones and unfortunately all vendors are creating larger and larger screens&amp;hellip; luckily the Nexus 5X isn&amp;rsquo;t that much larger than the Nexus 5 and it&amp;rsquo;s price is pretty friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a strange rule: I don&amp;rsquo;t buy phones more than 100,000 HUF ($363). The Nexus 5X costs $334 + VAT. Pretty good price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/google_nexus_5x.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nexus vs. Nexus 5x&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Nexus 5X is in your hands, the look and feel is almost the same like a Nexus 5. Except the fingerprint scanner at the back. That is pretty handy and useful. Makes it very convenient to unlock my phone. The screen is wider, the system is a bit faster, better button positioning, but in general it feels like Nexus 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nillkin-qin-leather-flip-case:96b1c56c0446a93b7db9992f2b490a22&#34;&gt;Nillkin qin leather flip case&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be quite honest I had a cover for my Nexus 5 but it was pretty poky, and I removed it a few month ago. But I wanted to have something elegant for my 5X. Many many years ago, I had my fist Nexus 4 case from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mytrendyphone.co.uk&#34;&gt;MyTrendyPhone&lt;/a&gt;, and I ordered a lot from there. Unfortunately the Nexus 5X is not available in Hungary (so actually I had to order it from abroad), so due to this there are no covers available in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/oldalt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Side&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On MyTrendyPhone I found a pretty elegant, stylish cover for my 5X. It&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mytrendyphone.co.uk/shop/lg-nexus-5x-182689p.html&#34;&gt;Nillkin Qin Leather Flip Case&lt;/a&gt;. It was love for the first sight. I knew I wanted it. The bad thing is that the shipment costs alost the same as the cover itself, but well I had no option. I had to buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/belulrol.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inside&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It arrived in about 2 days, they shipped it via UPS. I was suprised that the packaging itself was elegant too. I love to buy things from MyTrendyPhone, because they sell quality stuff. I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty satisfied with this company. I&amp;rsquo;m also satisfied with Google and LG, they manufactured another awesome mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/nexus5x/csukva.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Closed&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Why You Should Never Push Your AWS Credentials to GitHub</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/why-you-should-never-push-aws-credentials-to-github/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 08:56:23 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/why-you-should-never-push-aws-credentials-to-github/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is a story of a friend of mine who has a strange hobby: He loves &lt;code&gt;nodejs&lt;/code&gt; and other javascript related frameworks. A few days ago unfortunately I sent him a &lt;a href=&#34;http://claudiajs.com&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;code&gt;Claudia.js&lt;/code&gt;. Which is actually a cool thing by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gojko.net/&#34;&gt;Gojko Adzic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploy Node.js microservices to AWS easily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was so excited. He never used Amazon Web Services before so he signed up for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/free/&#34;&gt;AWS Free Tier&lt;/a&gt;. He found a few tutorials, and he just followed the steps in the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/156232471&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-email-you-never-want-to-get:f2279535fa1b5adb6ac0b81e3bcc6f75&#34;&gt;The Email You NEVER Want to Get&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tree days later on a sunny morning, he asked me if there is anything to do with &lt;code&gt;AWS credentials&lt;/code&gt;. He got an e-mail from AWS to remove his AWS credentials. He was pretty calm, had no idea that this is something pretty serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm, that sounded pretty bad, so I asked him to forward the e-mail to me. Actually it was THE email you never want to get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services has opened case xxxxxx on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details of the case are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case ID: xxxxxx&lt;br /&gt;
Subject: Your AWS account is compromised&lt;br /&gt;
Severity: Low&lt;br /&gt;
Correspondence: Dear AWS Customer,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your AWS Account is compromised! Please review the following notice and take &amp;gt;immediate action to secure your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your security is important to us. We have become aware that the AWS Access Key AKIAXXXX (belonging to IAM user &amp;ldquo;xxx&amp;rdquo;) along with the corresponding Secret Key is publicly available online at github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/aws-exposed/commit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;github commit&#34; title=&#34;GitHub Commit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy shit. It seems he had accidentally committed his AWS keys to GitHub. At this point I made a phone call and asked him to quickly review his AWS account. He logged in and saw 20 running instances instead of his t2.micro. His account was full of &lt;code&gt;g2.8xlarge&lt;/code&gt; instance types. That&amp;rsquo;s not that cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/aws-exposed/nano.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nano&#34; title=&#34;Nano&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I asked him to immediately deactivate all AWS API keys and terminate all instances in his current region and asked him to check all regions too. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Replacement servers were fired up after a few minutes. I knew that it won&amp;rsquo;t be that simple, so I felt I have to do it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I logged in with this root AWS credentials and navigated to the &lt;code&gt;Auto Scaling Groups&lt;/code&gt;, but that was empty. My next tip was &lt;code&gt;Spot Request&lt;/code&gt; instances. Bingo. There were &lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; spot requests / region with &lt;code&gt;$3.2&lt;/code&gt; max price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/aws-exposed/spot-requests.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;spot bids&#34; title=&#34;Spot Bids&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Luckily&amp;rdquo; his instance and spot limit were around 20, so I cancelled all spot bids and terminated all servers too. Double checked all regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-worst-part:f2279535fa1b5adb6ac0b81e3bcc6f75&#34;&gt;The worst part&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the account was cleaned up, it was time to check the billing. His account was exposed for about 2-3 days, which can cause a lot of instance hours. I clicked on the &lt;code&gt;Billing &amp;amp; Cost Management&lt;/code&gt; tab and saw the following on the dashboard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/aws-exposed/billing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;billing&#34; title=&#34;Billing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current balance is &lt;strong&gt;$6,437&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh my. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure how to tell him. I was shocked. I asked my colleague about this, and he told me that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS will probably credit him back if he gets it closed up quickly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is the case and he won&amp;rsquo;t need to pay that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;takeaway:f2279535fa1b5adb6ac0b81e3bcc6f75&#34;&gt;Takeaway&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t emphasize enough how important is to keep your credentials safe. What can you do to prevent this happening from the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use ephemeral tokens if possible. This is provided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/STS/latest/APIReference/API_AssumeRole.html&#34;&gt;AWS Security Token Service&lt;/a&gt;. You can define temporary cedentials with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The temporary security credentials are valid for the duration that you specified when calling AssumeRole, which can be from 900 seconds (15 minutes) to a maximum of 3600 seconds (1 hour). The default is 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/monitor-estimated-costs-using-amazon-cloudwatch-billing-metrics-and-alarms/&#34;&gt;Monitor Estimated Charges Using Billing Alerts&lt;/a&gt; on a daily basis. There are tools out there already.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remove keys after using them. If you&amp;rsquo;re done with experimenting, do not leave the keys there. Just remove them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decrease your default limits. If you know you won&amp;rsquo;t need ~20 instances only 1-2, open a support ticket and ask them to decrease your instance limits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use IAM roles and policies. Restrict the accesses of the keys to as minimum as you can. A few examples are &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/access_policies_examples.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not store your credentials on github without encrpyting them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Trigger Jenkins Build Securely Using GitHub and AWS</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/trigger-jenkins-build-securely-using-github-and-aws/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 09:05:26 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/trigger-jenkins-build-securely-using-github-and-aws/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;because-security-does-matter:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Because security does matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen thousands of &lt;a href=&#34;http://beta.jenkinci.io&#34;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt; masters. The non enterprise ones are usually triggering the builds via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; webhooks. You can do this via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/GitHub+Plugin&#34;&gt;GitHub Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s mandatory to allow github to reach your jenkins master if you want to use this method. But there is a trade-off. Security vs. comfy webhooks&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The enterprise masters are mostly using SCM polling instead, because their jenkins masters are not available from the external network. GitHub can&amp;rsquo;t reach their master. This is a show stopper, if you want to trigger a build immediately after a &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although using frequent SCM polling on hundreds of repos will cause huge I/O and CPU overload on your jenkins masters, so this blog post is mostly for Enterprise Jenkins customers and for the ones who want to secure and lock down their jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-proper-way:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;The proper way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily there is a plugin out there for a long time, but for some reason it remained unnoticed until now. The anonym plugin statistic says there is around only &lt;strong&gt;457&lt;/strong&gt; installations for this plugin. How come? What is this plugin?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mighty plugin is called the &lt;strong&gt;GitHub SQS Plugin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plugin integrates Jenkins with Github projects via Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Simple Queue Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumes a message from an SQS Queue and triggers any jobs that have a matching github repository configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically adds and removes the Github SQS Service hooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trigger build job using GitHub Amazon SNS service hook that use a SQS topic subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohh, but this is super cool. Jenkins is simply polling an &lt;code&gt;Amazon SQS&lt;/code&gt; queue. This does not cause I/O at all. If there is a &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;, GitHub sends the payload using &lt;code&gt;Amazon SNS&lt;/code&gt;, and the payload finally ends up in the &lt;code&gt;Amazon SQS&lt;/code&gt;. Jenkins just grabs the payload and triggers any jobs that have a matching github repository configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The requirements are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Web Services subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub repository or repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenkins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;amazon-sqs-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Amazon SQS configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a first step, login to your AWS console, select SQS service and create a new queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/create_sqs_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;Create New Queue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the queue name. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it &lt;code&gt;jenkins&lt;/code&gt;. Click on &lt;code&gt;Create Queue&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/create_sqs_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;Enter Queue Name&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select the newly created SQS queue and record the &lt;code&gt;ARN&lt;/code&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/create_sqs_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;SQS Summary&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;amazon-sns-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Amazon SNS configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select SNS service in the AWS console and create a new topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/create_sns_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SNS&#34; title=&#34;Create New Topic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the topic name. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it &lt;code&gt;jenkins&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/create_sns_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SNS&#34; title=&#34;Enter Topic Name&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select the newly created SNS topic and record the &lt;code&gt;ARN&lt;/code&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/create_sns_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SNS&#34; title=&#34;SNS Summary&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;amazon-iam-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Amazon IAM configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to create an &lt;code&gt;AWS Access Key ID&lt;/code&gt; and  &lt;code&gt;Secret Access Key&lt;/code&gt; for your jenkins and GitHub service. Select the &lt;code&gt;IAM&lt;/code&gt; service and create a new user. By default generate an access key. Let&amp;rsquo;s call this user &lt;code&gt;jenkins&lt;/code&gt; too. Record the credentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID=AKIA...
AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY=Aq9x...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attach a right &lt;code&gt;SQS/SNS&lt;/code&gt; managed IAM policy to this newly created user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a best practice, you should restrict the policy to have access only to the previously created &lt;code&gt;SQS/SNS&lt;/code&gt; resources. You can read more about &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/access_policies_manage.html&#34;&gt;Amazon IAM policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amazon Web Services configuration is now complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;GitHub configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case if your jenkins master has the rights to manage webhooks on GitHub, you can skip the next SQS configuration section. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t allow my jenkins to manage github hooks, because that requires administrative rights on a specific repo or even in the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-webhook-sqs-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;GitHub webhook SQS configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select your repository and select the &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Webhooks &amp;amp; services&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Add service&lt;/code&gt; from the dropdown menu and select &lt;code&gt;Amazon SQS&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/github_1_sqs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;SQS github&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the AWS credentials and the &lt;code&gt;ARN&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;SQS&lt;/code&gt; and save it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/github_2_sqs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;SQS github&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-webhook-sns-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;GitHub webhook SNS configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select your repository and select the &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Webhooks &amp;amp; services&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Add service&lt;/code&gt; from the dropdown menu and select &lt;code&gt;Amazon SNS&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/github_1_sns.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;SNS github&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the AWS credentials, &lt;code&gt;region&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code&gt;ARN&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;SNS&lt;/code&gt; and save it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/github_2_sns.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQS&#34; title=&#34;SNS github&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GitHub configuration is now complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;jenkins-general-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Jenkins general configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;GitHub SQS Plugin&lt;/code&gt; via the plugin manager and restart your jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to your jenkins&amp;rsquo;s configuration page &lt;code&gt;https://yourdomain/configure&lt;/code&gt; and locate the &lt;code&gt;Amazon SQS Configuration&lt;/code&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the AWS credentials and the SQS queue name or URL. Hit &lt;code&gt;Test Access&lt;/code&gt; to verify it&amp;rsquo;s working.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Manually manage GitHub SQS hook&lt;/code&gt; if your jenkins does not have access to manage webhooks on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/jenkins_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jenkins&#34; title=&#34;Jenkins SQS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;jenkins-job-configuration:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Jenkins job configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to your job&amp;rsquo;s configuration page and locate the &lt;code&gt;Build Triggers&lt;/code&gt; section. Enable the &lt;code&gt;Build when a message is published to an SQS Queue&lt;/code&gt; option and hit &lt;code&gt;Save&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Apply&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/jenkins-github-aws/jenkins_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jenkins&#34; title=&#34;Jenkins SQS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;profit:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;Profit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all set. Your jenkins job is configured and will be triggered when somebody pushes a code to the repository. It clean and safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;references:1f40da5ea83fe9e4190a55b044534933&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://beta.jenkins.io&#34;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/GitHub+SQS+Plugin&#34;&gt;GitHub SQS Plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/introduction.html&#34;&gt;AWS IAM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/sqs/&#34;&gt;AWS SQS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/sns/&#34;&gt;AWS SNS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>On My Way To Health</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/on-my-way-to-health/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 17:34:31 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/on-my-way-to-health/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reduced-nsaid-doseage:4111c14b995bb0d06acc50e622eb4f5d&#34;&gt;Reduced NSAID doseage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctor changed the NSAID doses on saturday. He prescribed a new NSAID called Xilox (Nimesulide). So since Saturday I had to take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ibuprofen&lt;/strong&gt;: 300mg x 2 (morning, evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nimesulide&lt;/strong&gt;: 50mg x 2 (morning, evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems it&amp;rsquo;s now enough to take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ibuprofen&lt;/strong&gt;: 300mg x 1 (evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nimesulide&lt;/strong&gt;: 50mg x 2 (morning, evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking NSAIDs have a tradeoff: No pain, no inflammation. But long-term, high-dose NSAID use to a greater risk for heart attack, stroke, heart failure and death from cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;daily-excercise:4111c14b995bb0d06acc50e622eb4f5d&#34;&gt;Daily excercise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning after I wake up, I do a few excercises to warm up my ankle. For example I have to push a ball to the wall. So entertaining..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put on my shoes and walk small distances with only 1 crutch. Frist I stared with 2 cruches but I can put more weight on it, so one is enough. I still can&amp;rsquo;t put 100% weight on it, still need a few more days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-more-pain:4111c14b995bb0d06acc50e622eb4f5d&#34;&gt;No more pain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced pain in the last ~4 days, even with reduced amount of NSAID. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. The ankle isn&amp;rsquo;t hot, no more swelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ride-getting-ready:4111c14b995bb0d06acc50e622eb4f5d&#34;&gt;Ride! Getting ready&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to get on my bike again, but I have to be patient. I know that in about 2 weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to ride again, of course I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to continue my training plan. I think during the rest of the season I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly do &lt;code&gt;E2&lt;/code&gt; aka. Endurance-Miles rides only. That means just do as much long rides as I can, in my Heart Rate zone 2. That will prevent my ankle from any overload/overtrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;compared-to-2013-it-was-pretty-quick:4111c14b995bb0d06acc50e622eb4f5d&#34;&gt;Compared to 2013 it was pretty quick&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the same issue in 2013 when I was in the US. After flying to San Francisco, I experienced a huge pain in my ankle after the very first day. That year it took about 5-6 months to recover. I tried every treatment without any luck. I was very frustrated and had no idea what was going on. Luckily just before I had to fly again to US (Seattle) it suddenly improved, so I could accept an offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Acute Ankle Inflammation</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/acute-inflammation/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 07:51:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/acute-inflammation/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-my-ankle-inflammation-sucks:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Why My Ankle Inflammation Sucks?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sucks for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;loosing-fittness:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Loosing Fittness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every bike rider, the season starts around October. We start the preparation period around early or mid October. I thought I was going to race this year, so I started a very strict training plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/ankle/strava.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fittness Dropping&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; training would started from 14th of February. Well I had no chance. As you can see on the graph, my fittness is going sharply down. Although my form is pretty good, but currently I&amp;rsquo;m at the same level as I was in November. No good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-t-let-out-some-steam:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Let Out Some Steam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, riding is indispensable. I&amp;rsquo;m working from home, and I rarely go outside. There is no daily contact with anyone. I need to ride 1-3 hours a day to let out the steam, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated and unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just you, your bike and the nature. I try to ride on roads with no traffic at all. I really miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-t-play-with-my-son:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Play With My Son&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son is 17 months old and loves to move around the house. Fortunately he&amp;rsquo;s pretty adaptive and he&amp;rsquo;s playing next to me on the couch, but this is not what he deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/ankle/bogyi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bogyi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what-s-happening-now:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;So What&amp;rsquo;s Happening Now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month has passed away and I finally I could see light at the end of the tunnel. I went to see a doctor on Saturday, so he finally did some X-Rays and told me that there is nothing serious. He prescribed another NSAID. I have to put a little more weight on it every day and do some excercises while taking the NSAIDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope for the bests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mexico - Company Kick-Off Meeting 2016</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/mexican-trip/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 21:54:30 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/mexican-trip/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ominous-signs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Ominous Signs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2 months ago, our CEO sent us an e-mail. It said that we will have another Kick-Off 2016 company wide meeting in &lt;code&gt;Mexico&lt;/code&gt; this time. Last year we were told we won&amp;rsquo;t have another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to reserve our plain tickets almost immediately so had no such time to think it over. The trip takes approximately &lt;strong&gt;35+ hours&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;code&gt;Budapest&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Ixtapa&lt;/code&gt;. That is enormously long flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;physiotherapy:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Physiotherapy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 1,5 month before the trip, my wife introduced to her physiotherapist - Eva -, so she started to work on me too. After 2 weeks we started to work on my ankle too. I can&amp;rsquo;t properly bend my ankle, because my leg was operated several times (15 times) when I was 15-18 and somehow my ankle was affected by the op, although the ankle itself was never operated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So she gave me a lot of excercises (but not only ankle related ones), and I was very enthusiastic doing them. Unfortunately a specific excercise strained my ankle. My ankle tendon had inflamed a bit. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad, I had only one bad night though, but I had to take &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsteroidal_anti-inflammatory_drug&#34;&gt;NSAID&lt;/a&gt; on that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the next days I was able to walk, didn&amp;rsquo;t have pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was cautious enough so I packed a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsteroidal_anti-inflammatory_drug&#34;&gt;NSAID&lt;/a&gt; (algoflex - ibuprofen) with me for the mexican trip. Unfortunately I was right&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;budapest-paris-2hrs-5hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Budapest - Paris /2hrs + 5hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to be at the airport around 13:00, left home around 12:30. The first flight from &lt;code&gt;Budapest&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Paris&lt;/code&gt; took only ~2hrs, not a big deal, but there I had to wait 5 hrs for the connection fly. I stumbled upon a former colleague from Prezi, so we were chatting on the plane and while we were waiting for our connection flight in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/shirokuma.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shirokuma&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went to Japan, so we had to wait on the same terminal. Way back we had a  business so we were talking about the good old days. My connection flight was around 23:30 so I finally caught up with my CloudBees collegues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/bud-cdg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Budapest to Paris&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paris-mexico-city-12hrs-7hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Paris - Mexico City /12hrs + 7hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the flight I took a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsteroidal_anti-inflammatory_drug&#34;&gt;NSAID&lt;/a&gt; and 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hazipatika.com/gyogyszerkereso/termek/detralex_500_mg_filmtabletta/443&#34;&gt;Detralex&lt;/a&gt; to reduce the risk of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thrombosis&#34;&gt;thrombosis&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t lucky and so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade my seat. Shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/cdg-mex.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paris to Mexico City&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was enormously long. I dank a lot of water to avoid dehydration. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to sleep at all, so I was pretty exhausted when we arrived around 4am in Mexico City. The airport was empty and &lt;strong&gt;cold as ice&lt;/strong&gt;. I was shaking from the cold air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went a lot of loops around the airport with the collegues looking for the spaniards (collegues from Spain) without any luck. I felt that my leg was swollen, so I tried to find a place to lay down. Unfortunately I only found a very uncomfy chair to lay down&amp;hellip; Finally we managed to sat down and ate something. Thanks Nicolas! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/mexican-pizza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nicolas&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were waiting for our last flight, we tried to sleep. No luck. The guys started to work, I just stayed lying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mexico-city-ixtapa-zihuatanejo-1hr:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Mexico City - Ixtapa-Zihuatanejo /1hr/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last fligt finally. The plane was filled only with my colleagues. You can imagine. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit dangerous.. Almost everybody from the company was on that plane. Except only a few ones who arrived a day before we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/mex-zih.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paris to Mexico City&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we had arrived to the hotel, I immediately went to my room and tried to lie down. I even slept a few hours, got up, went to eat something and went back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-recognition:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;The Recognition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, the 4 days long Kick-Off meeting had started with day long all-hands meeting. Around noon, I started to feel some pain near my ankle. Bad news. I had the same experience from 3 yrs ago, when I travelled to San Francisco with Anna&amp;hellip; that time it took me around &lt;code&gt;5 months&lt;/code&gt; to recover. Holy shit. Not again. I immediately took an NSAID and tried to rest as much as I could between the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next days, there were only team specific meetings, so I had to skip a lot of non-ineresting meetings, social evens, evening activities and so on&amp;hellip; I was just lying in bed and trying to work. Every evening I took a 600mg ibuprofen, otherwise I had so much pain, my whole ankle was burning. It felt like somebody was hammering my leg with a hammer. No good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/shore.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sea shore&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel&amp;rsquo;s restaurant was about 10 minutes away from my apartman, so I had to walk at least 3 times a day on my inflamed ankle which didn&amp;rsquo;t help a lot. But I had even worse news: I had to travel back in a phisical condition like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning my ankle was pretty good, but I knew it&amp;rsquo;s only an illusion. The evening came and the pain was just growing and growing&amp;hellip; 600mg every evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;coming-back:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Coming Back&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was struggling on my way home. I took 2 x 600mg ibuprofen and tried to survive it somehow. We had to wait a lot in Mexico city&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ixtapa-zihuatanejo-mexico-city-1hr-10-hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Ixtapa-Zihuatanejo - Mexico City /1hr + 10 hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was smooth and quick, although I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being able to concentrate at all. I was focusing on my leg all. We had to fly with a small plane with 2 propelers. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/propeler.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Propeler&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the ariport around &lt;code&gt;13:50&lt;/code&gt; and the connection flight was around &lt;code&gt;23:55&lt;/code&gt;. So I had more than &lt;strong&gt;10 hours!&lt;/strong&gt; with a swollen ankle and pain&amp;hellip; awesome. My plan was simple: survive it somehow. I tried to sit and lie as much as I could, but sometimes I had to get up and walk to grab a coffee or eat or just go to the toilet&amp;hellip; oh my. It was horrible. I knew my ankle won&amp;rsquo;t be happy..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mexico-city-paris-11hrs-3hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Mexico City - Paris /11hrs + 3hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckly the flight back to Paris is a bit quicker, but in my condition it was all the same. I took another 600mg ibuprofen around 1am after the take off. I was watching a few movies, tried to sleep but I only managed to sleep 1 hour or so. Not too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I had to wait only 3 hours in Paris for the connection flight which isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. I was half dead at that point. I saw in advance what were the consequences of this trip. Another 2-3 months of recovery, no bike&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paris-budapest-2hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Paris - Budapest /2hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had finally arrived, my myther in law came to take me home. I had just fallen into the bed&amp;hellip; I dreaded the next day. How did my ankle handle this long trip?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time I&amp;rsquo;ll never travel on &lt;code&gt;Economy Class&lt;/code&gt; only on &lt;code&gt;Business Class&lt;/code&gt;. If the company can&amp;rsquo;t afford it, I won&amp;rsquo;t go. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t worth for me to loose 3-4 months from my life due to a trip like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Betrtek Hozznk</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/a-nagy-rablas/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 17:09:08 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/a-nagy-rablas/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hogy milyen rzs az, amikor reggel gy bredsz, hogy 2 notebokkal kevesebb van a laksban, mint amikor este lefekdtl. Persze ehhez kell az, hogy jszakra elfelejtsed bezrni az ajtt, ami termszetesen egy ultrabiztonsgos sok ponton zr biztonsgi ajt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es ismet magyarul. Talan ezt az entry-t nem is lehetne mas nyelven irni. De kezdjuk az elejen. Egy szep vasarnapi naprol van szo. Delelott erzessel munka, tanulas, majd egy meglepi elkeszitese Annanak. Egy szep kis playboy-os torulkozovel szerettem volna meglepni ot. :) Fel is ugrottam hozza. Bebi termeszetesene otthon volt, Zsofi meg lelepett. Elotte persze odaadta a notebookjat h probaljuk meg a hangot megcsinalni rajta mert nem mukodik rendesen. Azzal a mozdulattal ki is hozta nekunk a konyhaba a gepet. Picit szerencsetlenkedtem rajta, le kellett volna szedni a hangkartya drivert es tokre ujrahuzni az egeszet, de annyira lassu volt a gep, hogy inkabb masnapra halasztottam. :) Kozben Anna es Bebi ugy dontott, hogy jo lenne nezni egy spanyol filmet. Elfogyott a tea is, igy leultunk megnezni a filmet. Picit hosszunak igerkezett es ejfel korul lett vege. En elkezdtem keszulodni haza, de a 2 lany rabeszelt h maradjak ott ejszakara, ne kelljen mar hazamennem ilyen keson. Igy mindenki szepen nyugovora tert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ezzel kezdetet vette egy iszonyatos hetfoi nap. Reggel ebredes utan, gyors reggeli, tej + muzli, ruhat + cipot felvenni. Majd megkeresni a kabatomat. De hol is van a kabatom? Kerdezem Annat, hogy hol van? Elvileg kint van az eloszobaban. Nem latom. Ahh biztos betette a szekrenybe. Ott sincsen. Fubaz. Rohanas a konyhaba. Akkor tunik fel, hogy ejjel meg 2 notebook is volt ott&amp;hellip; most mar nincs. Gyorsan odaugrottunk a bejarati ajtohoz, es lenyomtam a kilincset. Kinyilt. Nem volt ejszakara bezarva&amp;hellip; a 2 notebooknak es a kabatomnak + a benne levo iratoknak hult helyuk. Nabasszameg most mi lesz. Gyorsan kipattanunk a folyosora, lenezunk es latjuk hogy a foldszinten ott van a kabatom rateve a korlatra. Gyorsan lerohantam hozza. A tarcam es az irataim termeszetesen nem voltak benne. De legalabb ez megvan. Viszont igy mar biztosak lehetunk benne, hogy ejszaka betortek. Bebit is felebresztjuk lassan hogy elmondjuk neki mivan&amp;hellip; neki szerencsere nem tunt el semmije. Mig Anna a rendorseggel beszel, Bebi az agykontrollosokat hivja en letiltatom a bankkartyamat. Roviddel ezutan kierkeznek a rendorok is, felveszik a jegyzokonyvet, semmit nem kerdeznek csak par szot irnak fel, majd aztan rohannak is. Kozlik velunk, hogy lassan jon a technikus kollega, ujlenyomat stb. Addig varjunk. Rovid gondolkodas utan ugy dontottunk Annaval h lemegyunk megnezni a kozeli kukakat, hatha beledobtak a tarcamat, mert valoszinuleg arra nincsen szukseguk. Ahogy megyunk ki az ajton, latjuk hogy ott ulnek meg mindig a rendorok a kocsiban es nem csinalnak semmit. Picit duhito&amp;hellip; belenezunk az elso sarga regimodi kukaba. Bingo! Benne volt a penztarcam. Csak a penz hianyzott belole, semmi mas. Minden mas adatom megmaradat&amp;hellip; igy nem kell irtozatosan sok orat eloltenem mindenfele allami szerveknel hogy uj igazolvanyokat csinaltassak magamnak. A rendorok nagy mosollyal szettart karokkal mosolyogtak rank a kocsibol es kihuztak a felvett jegyzokonyvbol a tarcamat es az abban talalhato dolgokat. Miert nem ok neztek meg a kornyeken a szemeteseket? Nekem ez lenne az elso gondolatom ha rendor lennek, hogy a kornyeket atkutatom esetleges eldobott cuccokert&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ennek oromere picit setaltunk Annaval a kornyeken, levezeteskeppen. Aztan egyszercsak elszaguld mellettunk a rendorauto es kiuvolt belole az egyik rendor, hogy &amp;ldquo;Megjott a technikus kollega, menjenek haza!&amp;rdquo;. :) Egybol fordultunk is vissza es gyorsan vissza is ertunk. Bebi kozben panikszeruen hivogatott minket telefonon, de nem vettuk fel, hiszen tudtuk hogy ott van a technikus&amp;hellip; node vegulis megjottunk. A technikus kollega egy elegge apatikus rendor volt. Meg is mondta, hogy valoszinuleg az egesznek semmi ertelme most itt, es nem fog semmi nyomot talalni. Lehet hogy hozzaallas kerdese, de nem is talalt semmit. A penztarcamat megerdeztem, h erdemes-e megvizsgalni. Mondta hogy nem, plane hogy bor. Lehetne bekuldeni laborba, de nem fogjak megcsinalni.. Csavokam is elment vegulis. Mi meg maradtunk harman. Zsofit nem tudtuk elerni igy nem sikerult neki elmondani a jo hirt, hogy elloptak a notebookjat&amp;hellip; Viszont be kellett mennunk a rendorsegre megtenni a feljelentest. Igy osszeszedtunk magunkat es elidultunk a Haller utcaba ahol az APEH is van.. veletlenul pont oda is be kellett volna ugranom. Amint megerkeztunk a yardokhoz, osszetalalkoztunk az egyik rendorrel aki felvette a jegyzokonyvet a lakasban. Ranknezett es csak annyit kerdezett: &amp;ldquo;Es a szoke holgyet nem hoztak magukkal?&amp;rdquo;. Ugy nez ki, hogy nagyon bejott neki Bebi. Mondjuk hogy nem, amire lazan annyit valaszolt csak hogy &amp;ldquo;Na nembaj, majd legkozolebb&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. Azert remelem nem lesz legkozelebb.. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relativ hamar vegeztunk is ezzel a dologgal. Tovabb is alltunk, beneztunk az APEH-ba. Eselytelen volt, annyi embert allt a sorban. Ugy gondoltam, hogy inkabb masnap fogok beugrani a helyi APEH-ba. Szoval utunkat inkabb egy OTP bank iranyaba vettuk a Boraros ter fele. Utkozben hivott genie, hogy megint meghalt a zinc. A tulajdonos annyira ideges volt mar miatta, hogy vegulis azt a &amp;ldquo;parancsot&amp;rdquo; kaptuk hogy aznap ejszaka meg le kell cserelni az uj gepre, mely a &amp;ldquo;tantalum&amp;rdquo; nevet viseli es egy Quad Core durva server FreeBSD-vel&amp;hellip; dehat abban az allapotban aztan kurvara nem volt hozza kedvem. Sajnos ugy tunt, hogy nem lehet mast csinalni, ejszaka be kell mennem es meg kell csinalni az uj servert&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna hazakisert, picit helyrepofoztam nekik a kis feher iBook-omat, hogy az ellopott gepek helyett legalabb tudjanak valamivel dolgozni. Felpakoltam a sajat gepemet is, mert szerencsere pont nem vittem magammal azon a vasarnapi esten Annaekhoz igy nem is laptak el&amp;hellip; hu akkor lettem volna nagyon kiakadva. Mondjuk igy is sajnalom nagyon, hogy elvittek azt a 2 notebookot. Nade vegulis hazaertunk Annaval ismet, Bebi mar elment tanitani, Zsofi viszont meg mindig nem jott meg. En nekialltam dolgozni, Anna leugrott a boltba majd miutan visszajott elkezdett gyonyoru szep melodiakat zongorazni. Annyira jo es megnyugtato volt. Ekkor belepett Zsofi az ajton mosolyogva :) Mondtuk neki h uljon le eloszor, majd elmondtuk neki a &amp;ldquo;jo&amp;rdquo; hirt&amp;hellip; eleinte rohogott, hogy ahh hulyeskedunk, biztos azert mondjuk mert nem tudtuk megcsinalni a hangot a gepet es haha haha&amp;hellip; aztan megmutattuk neki a feljelentesrol szolo papirt meg iratokat es akkor tenyleg leesett neki is. Egesz jol fogadta a dolgot.8 korul bucsut mondtam nekik es elmentem az Interware serverparkjaba ahol mar genie nagyban szervezkedett&amp;hellip; az instrukciok egyszeruek voltak. Ne alljon a server sokat, es csak akkor allitsuk le a regit amikor a masik mar biztosan mukodik&amp;hellip; Egy laza egesz ejszakas serverparkos buli volt. Az adatok athuzasa csak 2-3 oraba telt, MySQL adatbazist szinten egy jo ora volt megcsinalni, aztan levelezes, webserver, regi rendszer osszekapcsolasa stb. Hajnal fel 7kor leptunk ki az IW kapujan. Sikeres volt a servercsere. Az uj rendszer egyszeruen fantasztikus. A 350 futo apache helyett siman 3-10 apache elbirja ezerszer lazabban azt a terhelest, ami alatt az OpenBSD osszeomlott. Szoval az uj terv, hogy minel hamarabb lecsereljuk a sajat rendszereinket is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nezzuk, hogy milyen tanulsagokat vonunk le.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nem japanban vagyunk, az ajtokat mindig zarni kell. Kint megteheted azt, hogy az ajtot be sem zarod, vagy otthagyod az iPodot egy nagy bevasarlo kozpont WC-jeben. Masnapra is ugyan ott lesz. De itthon meg a sajat lakasodba is betornek. Teljesen mas a mentalitas. Meg kell baratkozni a gondolattal, hogy itt mas a helyzet mint kint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nem szabad a gepeket olyan helyen hagyni ahonnan konnyen el lehet lopni meg otthon sem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ne hagyjunk a kabatban semmi fontos ertekeset, eleg konnyu celpont.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
