<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WoOh&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/tags/bike/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Adam Papai</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>0001-01-01 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>On My Way To Health</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/on-my-way-to-health/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 17:34:31 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/on-my-way-to-health/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reduced-nsaid-doseage&#34;&gt;Reduced NSAID doseage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctor changed the NSAID doses on saturday. He prescribed a new NSAID called Xilox (Nimesulide). So since Saturday I had to take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ibuprofen&lt;/strong&gt;: 300mg x 2 (morning, evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nimesulide&lt;/strong&gt;: 50mg x 2 (morning, evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems it&amp;rsquo;s now enough to take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ibuprofen&lt;/strong&gt;: 300mg x 1 (evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nimesulide&lt;/strong&gt;: 50mg x 2 (morning, evening)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking NSAIDs have a tradeoff: No pain, no inflammation. But long-term, high-dose NSAID use to a greater risk for heart attack, stroke, heart failure and death from cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;daily-excercise&#34;&gt;Daily excercise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning after I wake up, I do a few excercises to warm up my ankle. For example I have to push a ball to the wall. So entertaining..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put on my shoes and walk small distances with only 1 crutch. Frist I stared with 2 cruches but I can put more weight on it, so one is enough. I still can&amp;rsquo;t put 100% weight on it, still need a few more days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-more-pain&#34;&gt;No more pain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced pain in the last ~4 days, even with reduced amount of NSAID. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. The ankle isn&amp;rsquo;t hot, no more swelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ride-getting-ready&#34;&gt;Ride! Getting ready&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to get on my bike again, but I have to be patient. I know that in about 2 weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to ride again, of course I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to continue my training plan. I think during the rest of the season I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly do &lt;code&gt;E2&lt;/code&gt; aka. Endurance-Miles rides only. That means just do as much long rides as I can, in my Heart Rate zone 2. That will prevent my ankle from any overload/overtrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;compared-to-2013-it-was-pretty-quick&#34;&gt;Compared to 2013 it was pretty quick&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the same issue in 2013 when I was in the US. After flying to San Francisco, I experienced a huge pain in my ankle after the very first day. That year it took about 5-6 months to recover. I tried every treatment without any luck. I was very frustrated and had no idea what was going on. Luckily just before I had to fly again to US (Seattle) it suddenly improved, so I could accept an offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Acute Ankle Inflammation</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/acute-inflammation/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 07:51:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/acute-inflammation/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-my-ankle-inflammation-sucks&#34;&gt;Why My Ankle Inflammation Sucks?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sucks for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;loosing-fittness&#34;&gt;Loosing Fittness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every bike rider, the season starts around October. We start the preparation period around early or mid October. I thought I was going to race this year, so I started a very strict training plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/ankle/strava.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fittness Dropping&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; training would started from 14th of February. Well I had no chance. As you can see on the graph, my fittness is going sharply down. Although my form is pretty good, but currently I&amp;rsquo;m at the same level as I was in November. No good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-t-let-out-some-steam&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Let Out Some Steam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, riding is indispensable. I&amp;rsquo;m working from home, and I rarely go outside. There is no daily contact with anyone. I need to ride 1-3 hours a day to let out the steam, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated and unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just you, your bike and the nature. I try to ride on roads with no traffic at all. I really miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-t-play-with-my-son&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Play With My Son&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son is 17 months old and loves to move around the house. Fortunately he&amp;rsquo;s pretty adaptive and he&amp;rsquo;s playing next to me on the couch, but this is not what he deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/ankle/bogyi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bogyi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what-s-happening-now&#34;&gt;So What&amp;rsquo;s Happening Now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month has passed away and I finally I could see light at the end of the tunnel. I went to see a doctor on Saturday, so he finally did some X-Rays and told me that there is nothing serious. He prescribed another NSAID. I have to put a little more weight on it every day and do some excercises while taking the NSAIDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope for the bests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
