<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WoOh&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/categories/health/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Adam Papai</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-03-14 07:51:11 &#43;0100 CET</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Acute Ankle Inflammation</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/acute-inflammation/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 07:51:11 CET</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/acute-inflammation/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-my-ankle-inflammation-sucks:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Why My Ankle Inflammation Sucks?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sucks for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;loosing-fittness:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Loosing Fittness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every bike rider, the season starts around October. We start the preparation period around early or mid October. I thought I was going to race this year, so I started a very strict training plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/ankle/strava.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fittness Dropping&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; training would started from 14th of February. Well I had no chance. As you can see on the graph, my fittness is going sharply down. Although my form is pretty good, but currently I&amp;rsquo;m at the same level as I was in November. No good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-t-let-out-some-steam:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Let Out Some Steam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, riding is indispensable. I&amp;rsquo;m working from home, and I rarely go outside. There is no daily contact with anyone. I need to ride 1-3 hours a day to let out the steam, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated and unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just you, your bike and the nature. I try to ride on roads with no traffic at all. I really miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-t-play-with-my-son:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Play With My Son&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son is 17 months old and loves to move around the house. Fortunately he&amp;rsquo;s pretty adaptive and he&amp;rsquo;s playing next to me on the couch, but this is not what he deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/ankle/bogyi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bogyi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what-s-happening-now:e1fcc30f006df7a2160b310feaecd78b&#34;&gt;So What&amp;rsquo;s Happening Now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month has passed away and I finally I could see light at the end of the tunnel. I went to see a doctor on Saturday, so he finally did some X-Rays and told me that there is nothing serious. He prescribed another NSAID. I have to put a little more weight on it every day and do some excercises while taking the NSAIDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope for the bests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mexico - Company Kick-Off Meeting 2016</title>
          <link>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/mexican-trip/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 21:54:30 CET</pubDate>
          <author>Adam Papai</author>
          <guid>http://blog.wooh.hu/post/mexican-trip/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ominous-signs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Ominous Signs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2 months ago, our CEO sent us an e-mail. It said that we will have another Kick-Off 2016 company wide meeting in &lt;code&gt;Mexico&lt;/code&gt; this time. Last year we were told we won&amp;rsquo;t have another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to reserve our plain tickets almost immediately so had no such time to think it over. The trip takes approximately &lt;strong&gt;35+ hours&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;code&gt;Budapest&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Ixtapa&lt;/code&gt;. That is enormously long flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;physiotherapy:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Physiotherapy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 1,5 month before the trip, my wife introduced to her physiotherapist - Eva -, so she started to work on me too. After 2 weeks we started to work on my ankle too. I can&amp;rsquo;t properly bend my ankle, because my leg was operated several times (15 times) when I was 15-18 and somehow my ankle was affected by the op, although the ankle itself was never operated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So she gave me a lot of excercises (but not only ankle related ones), and I was very enthusiastic doing them. Unfortunately a specific excercise strained my ankle. My ankle tendon had inflamed a bit. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad, I had only one bad night though, but I had to take &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsteroidal_anti-inflammatory_drug&#34;&gt;NSAID&lt;/a&gt; on that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the next days I was able to walk, didn&amp;rsquo;t have pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was cautious enough so I packed a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsteroidal_anti-inflammatory_drug&#34;&gt;NSAID&lt;/a&gt; (algoflex - ibuprofen) with me for the mexican trip. Unfortunately I was right&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;budapest-paris-2hrs-5hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Budapest - Paris /2hrs + 5hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to be at the airport around 13:00, left home around 12:30. The first flight from &lt;code&gt;Budapest&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Paris&lt;/code&gt; took only ~2hrs, not a big deal, but there I had to wait 5 hrs for the connection fly. I stumbled upon a former colleague from Prezi, so we were chatting on the plane and while we were waiting for our connection flight in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/shirokuma.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shirokuma&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went to Japan, so we had to wait on the same terminal. Way back we had a  business so we were talking about the good old days. My connection flight was around 23:30 so I finally caught up with my CloudBees collegues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/bud-cdg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Budapest to Paris&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paris-mexico-city-12hrs-7hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Paris - Mexico City /12hrs + 7hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the flight I took a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsteroidal_anti-inflammatory_drug&#34;&gt;NSAID&lt;/a&gt; and 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hazipatika.com/gyogyszerkereso/termek/detralex_500_mg_filmtabletta/443&#34;&gt;Detralex&lt;/a&gt; to reduce the risk of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thrombosis&#34;&gt;thrombosis&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t lucky and so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade my seat. Shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/cdg-mex.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paris to Mexico City&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was enormously long. I dank a lot of water to avoid dehydration. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to sleep at all, so I was pretty exhausted when we arrived around 4am in Mexico City. The airport was empty and &lt;strong&gt;cold as ice&lt;/strong&gt;. I was shaking from the cold air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went a lot of loops around the airport with the collegues looking for the spaniards (collegues from Spain) without any luck. I felt that my leg was swollen, so I tried to find a place to lay down. Unfortunately I only found a very uncomfy chair to lay down&amp;hellip; Finally we managed to sat down and ate something. Thanks Nicolas! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/mexican-pizza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nicolas&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were waiting for our last flight, we tried to sleep. No luck. The guys started to work, I just stayed lying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mexico-city-ixtapa-zihuatanejo-1hr:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Mexico City - Ixtapa-Zihuatanejo /1hr/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last fligt finally. The plane was filled only with my colleagues. You can imagine. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit dangerous.. Almost everybody from the company was on that plane. Except only a few ones who arrived a day before we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/mex-zih.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paris to Mexico City&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we had arrived to the hotel, I immediately went to my room and tried to lie down. I even slept a few hours, got up, went to eat something and went back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-recognition:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;The Recognition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, the 4 days long Kick-Off meeting had started with day long all-hands meeting. Around noon, I started to feel some pain near my ankle. Bad news. I had the same experience from 3 yrs ago, when I travelled to San Francisco with Anna&amp;hellip; that time it took me around &lt;code&gt;5 months&lt;/code&gt; to recover. Holy shit. Not again. I immediately took an NSAID and tried to rest as much as I could between the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next days, there were only team specific meetings, so I had to skip a lot of non-ineresting meetings, social evens, evening activities and so on&amp;hellip; I was just lying in bed and trying to work. Every evening I took a 600mg ibuprofen, otherwise I had so much pain, my whole ankle was burning. It felt like somebody was hammering my leg with a hammer. No good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/shore.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sea shore&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel&amp;rsquo;s restaurant was about 10 minutes away from my apartman, so I had to walk at least 3 times a day on my inflamed ankle which didn&amp;rsquo;t help a lot. But I had even worse news: I had to travel back in a phisical condition like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning my ankle was pretty good, but I knew it&amp;rsquo;s only an illusion. The evening came and the pain was just growing and growing&amp;hellip; 600mg every evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;coming-back:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Coming Back&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was struggling on my way home. I took 2 x 600mg ibuprofen and tried to survive it somehow. We had to wait a lot in Mexico city&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ixtapa-zihuatanejo-mexico-city-1hr-10-hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Ixtapa-Zihuatanejo - Mexico City /1hr + 10 hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was smooth and quick, although I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being able to concentrate at all. I was focusing on my leg all. We had to fly with a small plane with 2 propelers. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.wooh.hu/images/mexico/propeler.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Propeler&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the ariport around &lt;code&gt;13:50&lt;/code&gt; and the connection flight was around &lt;code&gt;23:55&lt;/code&gt;. So I had more than &lt;strong&gt;10 hours!&lt;/strong&gt; with a swollen ankle and pain&amp;hellip; awesome. My plan was simple: survive it somehow. I tried to sit and lie as much as I could, but sometimes I had to get up and walk to grab a coffee or eat or just go to the toilet&amp;hellip; oh my. It was horrible. I knew my ankle won&amp;rsquo;t be happy..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mexico-city-paris-11hrs-3hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Mexico City - Paris /11hrs + 3hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckly the flight back to Paris is a bit quicker, but in my condition it was all the same. I took another 600mg ibuprofen around 1am after the take off. I was watching a few movies, tried to sleep but I only managed to sleep 1 hour or so. Not too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I had to wait only 3 hours in Paris for the connection flight which isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. I was half dead at that point. I saw in advance what were the consequences of this trip. Another 2-3 months of recovery, no bike&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paris-budapest-2hrs:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Paris - Budapest /2hrs/&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had finally arrived, my myther in law came to take me home. I had just fallen into the bed&amp;hellip; I dreaded the next day. How did my ankle handle this long trip?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary:43caf39167a754ecfddbe242b24cc8fe&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time I&amp;rsquo;ll never travel on &lt;code&gt;Economy Class&lt;/code&gt; only on &lt;code&gt;Business Class&lt;/code&gt;. If the company can&amp;rsquo;t afford it, I won&amp;rsquo;t go. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t worth for me to loose 3-4 months from my life due to a trip like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
